<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[RB Design]]></title>
  <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-12T21:36:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[R W Boyer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WTF]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2012/01/06/wtf/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-06T19:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2012/01/06/wtf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WTF is a short way of saying what the fuck. And the answer is&#8230;</p>

<blockquote><p>The YAML front matter needs to have comments: true or comments will be false. Meaning no comments.</p></blockquote>


<p>RW
:wq</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2012/01/05/Another-Year/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2012/01/05/Another-Year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="meta">5 Jan 2012 - Another Year Of Technology Disappointment</p>


<p>Another year stuck with Liquid, me I rather use ruby but the pain of maintaining and merging branches of Jekyll into my hacked up code base that uses Haml and Ruby directly with all the wonderfull ruby constructs and varialbles available in layouts and pages. It&#8217;s just too painful. So moving on to <em>Octopress</em>. We&#8217;ll see how that goes.</p>

<p>Disks vs. circles? Why am I getting disks on one server and circles as bullets with the exact same CSS?</p>

<ul>
<li>CSS is the same</li>
<li>Code is the same</li>
<li>Develop inspector shows the same inheritance.</li>
<li>WTF</li>
</ul>


<p>Node.js, what a crock. The inmates are running the assylum. This is what happens when you spend way too much time jacking around with manipulating browser internals. Some how you manage to actually convince yourself that this is fun and good. Then you go completely around the bend and start trying to convince <em>everyone</em> it&#8217;s fun and good. Hence we have node.js.</p>

<p>I love cell phones. Now you can be twiddled with constantly by everyone but that&#8217;s not why I love them. I love them becuase slowly human beings have become accustomed to really bad phone service, audio quality, and having to repeat themselves a million times. This has prepared us for VOIP. Yea.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">MaybeRuby</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">ruby?</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="ss">:true</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1571214.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>class MaybeRuby
  def ruby?
    return :true
  end
end</code></pre></noscript></div>




<blockquote><p>Just a test of things in Octopress - I love static site generators. They are the best things since sliced bread.<br/>Amazing.</p></blockquote>


<p>RB
:wq</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Officially A Grandfather]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/12/12/i-am-officially-a-grandfather/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/12/12/i-am-officially-a-grandfather</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My apologies for keeping away for so so very long. I guess it&#8217;s been about two weeks, that is like centuries in internet time. I do have a very good excuse. My oldest daughter gave birth to her very first child and my very first grandchild. Yes - I am a grandfather.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/DSC_6733-as-Smart-Object-1.jpg"></p>

<p>The new addition to the family is a 22 3/4&#8221; 8lb 10oz baby girl named Leela Andreyevna Khlistunova. Think she might have a tough time writing that in Kindergarden? Needless to say I have been a bit busy at the hospital, visits, etc. etc.</p>

<p>During the course of the last week and a half I did have a chance to make a few observations while taking photos of my new granddaughter - most of them related the Nikon D7000 and TTL flash. Not all of them good. While I do strive to use available light as my preference there are times when that just will not work out and flash is just a hair less ugly.</p>

<p>Here are a couple of things off the top of my head that I will be discussing at length in upcoming posts:</p>

<ul>
    <li>With all the vunder-computing, color-matrix-metering, hoop-de-do bullcrap it&#8217;s unbelievable that the Nikon TTL flash control consistently and hopelessly underexposes scenes with a lot of white in the frame. I kinda remember this is kinda what the whole automated, evaluative thing was for in the first place. Wasn&#8217;t it? Well after extensive in the field testing I&#8217;ll give some my guidelines for the D7000 depending on how you have the 300,000 parameters set. Hmmmm 300,000 parameters and compensation vs incident flash meter? Yes we will have to discuss that again.</li>
    <li>Despite all of the things I have read from all of the on-line &#8220;experts&#8221; as well as Nikon that there is not really a difference between &#8220;TTL&#8221; and &#8220;TTL-BL&#8221; exposure in circumstances were ambient light does not contribute to the main subject&#8217;s exposure, that is complete and utter hogwash. At least it is with my particular D7000 and both my SB800&#8217;s. Maybe mine are somehow different - yeah right.</li>
    <li>Digital skin tones continue to be horrible. At least they are &#8220;out of the can&#8221; on most JPEG settings and definitely on all the default RAW conversions in both Lightroom, ACR, and Aperture. I have mentioned this just a couple of times in the past right? Well I guess now that I am shooting people with the D7000 and digital vs film only for the first time in a while I will have to discuss some options for dealing with that in Aperture and if anyone cares ACR as well.</li>
    <li>My current favored lighting gear is WAY too big and cumbersome for use in my daughter&#8217;s small apartment. I just ordered some gear that should alleviate that - cheap simple gear. I share some of that as well as how I am using it as well. Why do I need lighting gear? Because sometimes the light is just crappy and there just isn&#8217;t a decent bounce surface to be found. I spent less than a hundred bucks and should be able to get the results I am after. My order should get here any day now.</li>
</ul>


<p>More Later</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Little Down On Digital Lately]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/19/a-little-down-on-digital-lately/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/19/a-little-down-on-digital-lately</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been a tad hard on digital imaging lately. I wanted to put that into context. The context is that I am a photographer and image maker first and foremost. For better or for worse we photographers are married to our tools and the people that make them. The reason I have been a little down on digital lately is because I am a heavy user of digital. I don&#8217;t sit away in my little corner of the universe isolated from all things digital - obviously. Not only am I a heavy user of digital capture devices and digital imaging processing software. I am a customer. Yes I have spent huge sums of money on digital imaging gear and post processing software and all that goes with it.</p>

<p>I consider it a right and a duty to point out the flaws and shortcomings of products I invest my money and more importantly my time and my images into. It is in that spirt that I cast dispersions on software and image capture devices that I use. The reason I choose film as a medium to compare it with is that happens to be the only other photographic medium out there with it&#8217;s own set of qualities, processes and procedures that are quickly being forgotten. Not all of those qualities, processes, and procedures are bad - a lot of them were very very good. I want my cake and I want to eat it to. I still use film where I feel it is appropriate. I use digital as well and want to see it become as refined as some of the things I have experienced with film.</p>

<p>You see I don&#8217;t want just more of the same with digital. I don&#8217;t want a continual improvement in ONLY the speed and &#8220;convenience&#8221; features. There are still terrible shortcomings that we all pretend are not there or become distracted from due to the next new thing that we didn&#8217;t want in the first place. Man the way highlights are rendered blow - they look like absolute shit - I guess I will have to either underexpose for the highlights and make it sorta look okay - or use fill flash - or do that goofy HDR crap until it gets more like film - I can live with it but it really sucks. Hey man look at the new camera - it shoots like 12 frames a second at like 25 bazillion pixels - I guess I can live with crappy ass highlight rendition for a bit longer&#8230;. On and on and on more of the same.</p>

<p>I have also been hard on Apple Aperture 3 for more than a month - no love. Understand that I am also one of it&#8217;s biggest proponents. Just because I think ACR has come into it&#8217;s own in the last year or two doesn&#8217;t have me shouting Lightroom from the rooftops (I know Lightroom very very well - most of my images are cataloged   in both via referenced images). In the spirit of Thanksgiving - here in the US I am going to write only positive posts regarding digital and specifically Aperture 3 over the next week or so. Starting with Aperture 3 RAW processing that I have taken more than a few pot shots at over the last month. I will also chuck in some quick and dirty tutorials on the finer points of Aperture 3 adjustments along the way&#8230;</p>

<p>Happy Thanksgiving.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nikon D7000 Preset News and Updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/17/nikon-d7000-preset-news-and-updates/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/17/nikon-d7000-preset-news-and-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There have been quite a few people that have been participating in the beta version of my <a href="http://photo.rwboyer.com/2011/11/09/nikon-d7000-presets-for-aperture-3/">D7000 Picture Control Presets for Aperture 3</a>. More than I expected with all the caveats that I put out there. A few of them have written me with comments and critique - I plan on incorporating that critique into updates if possible and if it does not conflict with other peoples results&#8230;</p>

<p>What is surprising is that a bunch of people that shoot other Nikon cameras have asked me if the work with those models - like the D3, the D700, etc. The short answer is maybe. The long answer is that most Nikons that have &#8220;Picture Control&#8221; share similar characteristics in terms of their Aperture 3 RAW process so in general the D7000 presets provide  something more in the neighborhood of Nikon NX2 picture control settings than the default Aperture 3 processing. Having said that I have been working on and off with a Nikon D3s shooter to get a little more precise as to what is different. The presets are definitely not as close as the D7000 but do get it closer. If there is interest I may also offer a D3s version of the presets. Please let me know.</p>

<p>One last note on Aperture 3 presets and actually presets in general. As you may have guessed I don&#8217;t rely on Aperture 3 for all of my post processing. Not even close. I shoot and have shot with many many cameras ranging from Hasselblad H2&#8217;s to Sigma&#8217;s to Nikons. In many cases I use Aperture 3 only for it&#8217;s work-flow and organizational capabilities. The UI is extremely fluid compared to other solutions but I rarely use it for the final image produced in terms of post processing. Is it good enough? Yes maybe in a lot of cases. Especially for delivering a ton of images. Is it good enough or comprehensive enough for delivering the ONE image - ummmmm. Not so much.</p>

<p>What this results in is me working with a bunch of RAW processors - Capture One in some cases, NX2 obviously, Hasselblad Phocus (although since Hasselblads new found openness with Adobe in October - ACR6 is actually BETTER for H4D files than Phocus), and of course the ubiquitous Adobe Camera RAW in various versions and flavors. ACR has gotten so much better over the years that in a lot of cases it meets or exceeds some manufacturer&#8217;s RAW processing software - as I just mentioned the latest development.</p>

<p>What does this have to do with presets? Well I have a bunch of presets that I use that some of you might be interested in. I shoot film - I love the way film looks. What kind of presets might you guess I have spent considerable effort on? Presets that mimic the look of some of my favorite film.  Portra, Ektar, Kodachrome, Astia, etc. The way I have gone about this is not the way you may think. Most of my preset effort has been in the form of ACR DNG camera profiles with some add-ons on top of that. I have been playing with these <a href="http://photo.rwboyer.com/2008/08/10/adobe-lightroom2-and-dng-camera-profiles/">ever since the beta of DNG camera profile</a> became available&#8230;</p>

<p>I have also sort of mimicked these DNG profiles in Aperture as much as possible - which is not the same but good enough for a visual impression. Here is the question - are any of you interested in the DNG profiles for film simulation? How about the not quite as good Aperture 3 presets that correspond to those? The DNG profiles are camera specific so they will only work for Nikon and any other cameras that I develop them for. The Aperture 3 presets are not really that specific. Let me know if you are interested in these - I don&#8217;t want to go through the considerable effort of packaging them in a friendly form if I am the only one that likes the way film renders color.</p>

<p>[poll id=&#8221;31&#8221;]</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Word About Photo Gear]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/13/a-word-about-photo-gear/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/13/a-word-about-photo-gear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Look at the state of that&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_5047-Version-2.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_5048-Version-2.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_5048-Version-2.jpg"></p>

<p>What we have here is a Photoflex light disk - I am sure along the way you have all seen these. They fold down to about 1/4 the full size. I went to use this particular one this morning and this is what I found. My vague recollection is that I used it about 3 months ago and nothing really bad happened to it while I was shooting. there may have been a tiny bit of light mist that day. It definitely was cloudy. I was shooting indoors that day and the exposure to the elements consisted of a trip from my trunk and back. I can tell you that none of my other gear suffered and it definitely was not soaking wet when I put it back with all my other crap.</p>

<p>I have had this particular disk along with 2 60&#8221; disks for about 8 years. Up until this they were all pretty decent and not even dirty. The sparkly sides of all of them is beginning to flake off where they get creased as they are folded but that&#8217;s it. I never really thought about it before but these are definitely NOT the way to go if you do any kind of shooting or transportation that risks the slightest bit of moisture due to the steel frame that seems to disintegrate with any tiny bit of dampness.</p>

<p>I used to use California Sunbounce reflectors but about 5 of them got mislaid somewhere along the way. They are CRAZY expensive but I have shot with them in the rain, by the ocean, in the surf and can tell you personally they are 100 times more durable and have some other nice handling features as well. I guess I will have to save my pennies to replace them.</p>

<p>One other thing that you cannot see in the images - it also warped severely so it&#8217;s not even flat anymore. Hmmm - I don&#8217;t even want to speculate how that is related to moisture.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Really Funny Stuff - Must Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/really-funny-stuff-must-read/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/really-funny-stuff-must-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the foul mood and negativity of my last two posts - that is what dealing with the government does to me. On a lighter note but still on topic relative to not only the last two posts but a lot of the subtext in more than a few of my posts. Here are a few posts that you have to read, if these don&#8217;t make you chuckle, I don&#8217;t know what would. File this under funny because you know it&#8217;s true.</p>

<p>On this post you can skip the mildly pedantic preface where the author (whom I really like) tries to explain how he has <em>never</em> been affected by biases of <em>his</em> generation. Go directly to the end where you will find a faux forum discussion on one of HCB&#8217;s famous photographs. Hilarious.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ultrasomething.com/photography/2010/06/click-clique/">Forum Discussion on an HCB image</a>.</p>

<p>Here are some imagined comments on various famous icons of photography and their photographs.</p>

<p><a href="http://theonlinephotographer.blogspot.com/2006/06/great-photographers-on-internet.html">Inspired comedy</a>.</p>

<p>Enjoy</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look Ma - I Learned Me Some Photoshop]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/look-ma-i-learned-me-some-photoshop/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/look-ma-i-learned-me-some-photoshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shoot me now. I have to comment on this. I have no self-control at all. Forgive me. Continuing the train of thought regarding the state of commercial photography, I submit for your evaluation <a href="http://www.featureshoot.com/2009/09/john-short-london/">this steaming pile of meaninglessness</a>. Again - I am not in anyway attacking the individual that produced these. He is a <em>commercial</em> photographer and I have to assume that he must make a living - hence he is producing this dog-doo with a targeted purpose in mind in order to sell his services and pay his rent, etc. I am attacking the consumers - not the purveyors of the non-sense.</p>

<p>Let me limit the conversation to the first image. Hmmmm, hmmmmmmmmmmm, hmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm. Okay then - I don&#8217;t even know where to start. I only have questions - not questions of the good kind. Only questions of the bad kind. Don&#8217;t get me wrong I LOVE photographs that actually cause me to question things - especially question myself. That is NOT the kind of questions that this provokes. More like&#8230;</p>

<ol>
    <li>Yes we all know how to make composites. It seems that this image is some sort of statement about making really really bad composites while demonstrating the skill to make decent composites at the same time. Sort of like using techniques gleaned from PhotoShopDisasters in a <em>creative</em> way. Fantastic. Forking great. I really hope this doesn&#8217;t become tooooo popular.</li>
    <li>Is this for the purpose of some sort of children&#8217;s book? You know like the &#8220;where&#8217;s Waldo&#8221; type or the &#8220;what&#8217;s different between these two pictures&#8221; type. Only this one you have to pick out the really bad composites and then the reasonable parts of the bad composite like some sort of game?</li>
    <li>Is the society that I am a part of so visually retarded that this makes any commercial or artistic sense at all?</li>
    <li>Is this a joke? Like the kind you did when you were a teenager with your drunken buddies - &#8220;I&#8217;ll bet you I can convince Ted this is an actual photograph - he is soooooo plastered&#8221;</li>
    <li>How the hell did I just step in dog crap on my front lawn even though I don&#8217;t own a dog?</li>
</ol>


<p>Commercial image making can be fantastic - I have seen it. I swear, back just a decade or two. You know back when we could actually communicate in full sentences. Back when we all sort of understood that something like organized anarchists was a ridiculous concept and donning attire that identified you as some sort of violent criminal was not all that productive and was the polar opposite of what actual violent criminals would do.</p>

<p>I swear there was good commercial imaging - I know that some of you will say that the image did it&#8217;s job because I payed attention to it. Trust me - I will forget it ever existed by about noon tomorrow or sooner. Where as something like this&#8230;.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scorpions-lovefrontje.jpg"></p>

<p>I can remember for decades.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Film Friday]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/film-friday/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/11/film-friday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got around to looking at some shots testing my first roll of Ektar 100 from a while back - yes yes I am slow and loose track of things easily. Thought I would leave you with this for the weekend. Just happened to be shooting my D7000 as a &#8220;known quantity&#8221; while seeing what stupid things I can do with Ektar 100 in 35mm. Like most of you I have this strange sort of anxiety about shooting &#8220;important&#8221; things with something you never used before. Like usual I just shot some stupid stuff about 3 feet from my front door. Hey at least I gathered the energy to go outside.</p>

<p>So here is the Ektar 100 with NOTHING done to it. I scanned it myself at a stupidly high resolution and can assure you that this is a neutral scan. Heck I didn&#8217;t even sharpen it. Nothing. Well I did set the black point in the scanner software to something reasonable. Shot with a Nikon FE and 60&#8217;s vintage Nikkor 50mm f1.4.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/2011-008-27cn.jpg"></p>

<p>Ta&#8230;.Daaaaaa. Here is the D7000 version with a similar contrast curve and black point (you should see it before that).</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_3434-as-Smart-Object-1.jpg"></p>

<p>What the hell happened to my color - why the heck did I point my camera over here in the first place. Maybe If I use NX2 and set the WB to daylight and the picture control to vivid it might help things a bit. Why not.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_3434-nx2.jpg"></p>

<p>No dice. Maybe if I use ACR6 and jack up the contrast and vibrance like everyone does on every single image. And also use a vivid camera profile. Maybe it will get better. Here we go, hold on to your hats - this will make it look good.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_3434-ACR.jpg"></p>

<p>Hmmmm. Maybe film does look good - sometimes.  I know there are a few of you that somehow are think that this is some sort of trick or that I have somehow not done what I &#8220;should&#8221; have to the D7000 image. Addressing the first - No tricks, no there was no filter on the film camera - NONE, not even a UV or 1A - Nothin&#8217;. I wish I were patient enough to actually shoot these on different days with the EXACT same light and water/wind conditions with the EXACT same boats. If I were I would put that patience to far far more nefarious purposes that hoodwinking a couple of people that film actually looks great. Or maybe I am not telling the truth about what I did in Photoshop to the film image - hmmmmm - I cross my heart - no tricky-ness. If I were going to resort to that - I would be a whole lot more tricky.</p>

<p>As to not treating the D7000 image properly - Yea I could make it look better. Screw it why bother. I could play around in Color EFEX Pro 8 different ways. Heck I could spend a year figuring out how to render it better. Why bother.  There was pink in the sky - now it&#8217;s gone in the D7000 images - see the color of the sunlight in the film - still golden but the clouds and sky had a pinkish purplish hue against a very set of cool shadows. Why did the D7000 not see this? I have no idea but this is not just &#8220;bad scanning&#8221; or &#8220;bad film&#8221;. I notice this type of thing with the way digital renders scenes with wildly varying color temps of light in the same frame constantly. If I were a landscape guy this would drive me nuts trying to figure out how to get the whole warm/cool contrast and color back into images. Personally I am more concerned with how much more work digital capture is in making skin look great (color and texture).</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photography - The (Depressing) State of the Union]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/10/photography-the-depressing-state-of-the-union/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/10/photography-the-depressing-state-of-the-union</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s a bit chilly here in Maryland today. Leaves are falling off the trees, meaning winter is coming. I hate the winter. Oh, I also had to go to the DMV today. I guess that this particular combination of things has me in a rather foul mood so please take the following ramble understanding that I mean no harm or ill will towards any particular individual. Take it more as a bad mood fueled take on things I find baffling as a whole.</p>

<p>Case #1 - Randomly chosen bunch of images from a randomly chosen &#8220;fashion&#8221; photographer but fairly representative of poppycock crapped out as a matter of course. <a href="http://www.featureshoot.com/2011/10/laetitia-bicas-amusing-fashion-photography/">Take a look here</a>.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Anything here that is some extremely refined craftsmanship and masterful treatment of the medium? Nope.</li>
    <li>Any great &#8220;moments&#8221; - Yes there can and are really really great moments in a lot of commercial fashion work. Yes they may have been &#8220;staged&#8221; but they are really really great. Any here? Nope.</li>
    <li>Any story? Any story whatsoever - overt, banal, cliched, or even in-your-face-explicit story? Nope? How &#8216;bout a subtle story that is a little open ended - the best kind? Nope. How about a story with lots of subtext with a few different interpretations - this happens with really great and cleaver photographers every once in a while - Not here.</li>
    <li>Okay how &#8216;bout a workman like treatment of the fashion that does a good workman like job of showing off the fashion? Well unless this really is some sort of limited market joined at the shoulder siamese twin fashion house I am not aware of, or maybe militants in leotard specialty outfitter ummmm Nope.</li>
    <li>I think a few of these are even composted onto the background at first glance. Is this sort of like a &#8220;look ma, I learned how to do whacky stuff that has no point in photoshop&#8221; kind of thing, I am just not getting it. Interesting? No. Creative? Ummm No - unless you are one of those really really liberal types that believes everyone in every action including taking a crap is somehow &#8220;creative&#8221;. Visually or intellectually informative in any way? Not really.</li>
</ul>


<p>And you wonder why I don&#8217;t really want much to do with commercial photography or the fashion market any more? In my tiny little limited mind photography has become not photography in any of the ways that give me any kind of pleasure - it&#8217;s more like a mutated form of the show Jack Ass where people sit around and think of increasingly stupid shit they can do that has no point. At least Jack Ass is funny.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fine Art Photography - Pah, Really]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/10/fine-art-photography-pah-really/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/10/fine-art-photography-pah-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every wonder why I am so brutal when mentioning the contemporary &#8220;art&#8221; community? Here it the reason. It&#8217;s also why I hold suspect anyone that likes to use the meaningless term &#8220;fine art&#8221; prefixed to photography. This is not to say that anyone who does sucks - I know plenty of people that use that prefix that are really really good. I still make fun of them - mostly my friends. I do this in truth to illuminate myself as to their particular thought process and the best answer I can come up with is that some a$$hole did it and now people feel that they have to use it to somehow make sure everyone knows that they don&#8217;t have somehow inferior photography in contrast to &#8220;fine art&#8221;. Nobody said these words to me but that is my own para-meaning-phrase of what explanations I have been given in nicer words during quite sober conversations.</p>

<p>Okay so here is exhibit A:</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_8087.jpg"></p>

<p>Oooops, sorry that was some out of focus trees I shot to see what the out of focus rendition was for an old lens I grabbed on eBay. Here is exhibit A:</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/DSC_8078.jpg"></p>

<p>Sorry - that was a bush in my front yard while testing focus calibration for a camera&#8230; Here it is - here is the really really fine fine art of all arts.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/rhine_mini.jpg"></p>

<p>You see that last one is <a href="http://www.petapixel.com/2011/11/09/gurksy-photo-of-rhine-sells-for-4-3m-becomes-worlds-most-expensive-pic/">so damn fine art that it just sold for $4,338,500</a>. Yep, I praise the photographer, he is freaking amazing. For him and his circle jerk of art buddies to be so full of shit in order to convince someone that this is somehow so rarefied - so insightful - so&#8230; valuable as to be worth north of FOUR MILLION DOLLARS. Now that is art. I am talking about the full of shit part not the image. In fact this group of art that gets to define what is art and how more better it is than say the previous two images is actually performance art of sorts - either that or they have become so very full of shit that they actually believe that somehow their vision and ability are so so amazing that this crock of nonsense is actually worth many many many many times what people that actually make stuff earn in a year.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t blame the artist or circle jerk of mental masturbators that is the modern art community for this. I wish I could but they are just retarded or opportunistic and predatory. I blame the people with the money that actually spend it in such a foolish way thus perpetuating the asinine thought process and culture. I don&#8217;t care if the print took 5 years for the &#8220;artist&#8221; to painstakingly paint pixel by pixel with his pecker the image is not worth that. This kind of thought process is idiotic. I would have rather seen the bidder spend his money on a week long drug fueled, 100 whore a night, bender to end all benders rather than this kind of true waste.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nikon D7000 Presets For Aperture 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/09/nikon-d7000-presets-for-aperture-3/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/09/nikon-d7000-presets-for-aperture-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, okay - I changed my mind again. I took a new and different approach that will probably make nobody happy but here goes. Consider this a beta test with updates most likely to follow. For now I am not going to promote these presets anywhere but on this post. They are far far far from perfect as <a href="http://photo.rwboyer.com/2011/11/04/aperture-3-nikon-d7000-presets-the-saga-continues/">I explained here</a>. There are too many variables to make a one size fits all set of presets and to make them perfect they are too hard and complicated to use - hence why bother with a preset in the first place.</p>

<p>Here is what I decided on for this beta - Closely match the contrast/gamma of the Nikon Picture Controls AND add just a couple of color adjustments that are designed to give the overall impression of Nikon color rather than match each and every hue in every lighting condition.  To that end the color adjustments I chose to deal with are rather asymmetric - some picture are different than others in terms of what color adjustments they are designed to deal with. Specifically Landscape and Vivid do things that may cause issues on images that really are not appropriate for Landscape and Vivid while Neutral, Portrait, and standard omit the potentially problematic adjustments.</p>

<p>If you are curious - all of the presets manipulate blues to a certain extent over a fairly broad range. This is one of the most noticeable differences in Nikon color vs. Aperture 3 color. Instead of matching hue, saturation, and luminance exactly as NX2 does I went with an approach that will hopefully be a reasonable balance across all images as opposed to matching the blues exactly and causing hideous split color problems in certain conditions. I took the safe way out. The Landscape and Vivid presets also deal with another nagging Aperture 3 problem with Nikon NEF files. The Yellow/Green merge. In a lot of circumstances this is virtually impossible to deal with a one size fits all preset. Again I took the safe way out. There is a certain hue that I consider the tipping point after looking at 1000&#8217;s of images. That is the hue that I decided to manipulate independently of pure yellow. After playing around with it and testing it on 100&#8217;s of images it seems to be a reasonable compromise for most situations where Aperture 3&#8217;s treatment would be not so pretty. I left this out of the standard, portrait, and neutral for reasons I will not bore you with.</p>

<p>If you decide that you want these presets please understand that I consider these the first beta release. I will be depending on your specific feedback with things you would like to see in future updates. Until I consider them final please keep the download link so that you can obtain free updates as I incorporate suggestions for refinements. If you do have suggestions for improvements and refinements please leave them in comments on this post. They do not have to be technical just a reasonable description of what you are seeing and what you would like to be different.</p>

<p>Here goes&#8230;</p>

<p>Remember - after the transaction please use the link &#8220;return to merchant&#8221; in order to download the presets.</p>

<h2>Only $4.99 - With Free Updates!</h2>


<p><form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post"> <input name="cmd" type="hidden" value="_s-xclick" /> <input name="hosted_button_id" type="hidden" value="447BGCUXRWBC2" /> <input alt="PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!" name="submit" src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_buynowCC_LG.gif" type="image" /><img src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif" border="0" alt="" width="1" height="1" /></p>

<p></form>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Available Light Workshop - Brain Dump]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/04/available-light-workshop-brain-dump/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/04/available-light-workshop-brain-dump</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/1999-021-08small.jpg"></p>

<p>So a couple of dozen people from all over the map have mentioned that they might be interested in an available light workshop and there were a few inquisitive souls that just had to know what that might be like. I guess the answer is really up to what people would be interested in as my agenda might last a week or a month or longer. That might be a little inconvenient and just a bit grueling for most non-fanatics.</p>

<p>Here is a bit of a brain dump of what kind of things I would guess might be interesting and useful from my perspective. Instead of getting all artsy-fartsy and acedemic in the syllibus I&#8217;ll just use some humor to get the rough outline down and hopefully get some feedback from you. Of course I would actually organize this into something a bit more coherent for the real thing.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Using the light modifiers already built into your environment both indoors and outdoors. AKA - why sunlit concrete is your friend.</li>
    <li>What is open shade and using it to the best effect. Identifying the good open shade, the bad, and the ugly.</li>
    <li>All about windows. North light, diffused sunlight, and bounced sunligt.</li>
    <li>All about rooms - this is the sequel to all about windows. Rooms matter. The size, the color, and most importantly where you situate your subject in them. A special section on corners - all rooms have corners that make for fantastic background effects.</li>
    <li>Beating mid-day sun into submission. AKA Great light without ugly itty-bitty blue colored on-camera fill-flash. Oh and also without reflectors that will drive you nuts even in a mild breeze.</li>
    <li>Why grass is your enemy and some things you might want to think about in vanquishing it.</li>
    <li>Okay, okay - reflectors can be useful. Here are a few ways to use them and here are a couple of improvisations for the finantially ummm&#8230; prudent.</li>
    <li>Some really good reasons you want to use manual mode and something other than matrix/pattern metering.</li>
    <li>Special bonus - everyone is supplied with a manual SLR, wide aperture lens, and one roll of 36exposure Kodak Portra (processing included) to shoot however they want during the workshop - or not and some examples of the joy of shooting color negative film with various effects.</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course I will supply either pro or semi-pro models. Hair + MUA (model calibre depends on price tolorance but all will probably know more than the average bear on directing models and will look good in front of the camera). I am thinking a two day week-end agenda with a discussion in the morning, lots of time and opportunity to work vairous scenes with models. Dinner and discussion with image review in the evening.</p>

<p>Comments? - questions? - suggestions?</p>

<p>[poll id=&#8221;30&#8221;]</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aperture 3 Nikon D7000 Presets - The Saga Continues]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/04/aperture-3-nikon-d7000-presets-the-saga-continues/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/04/aperture-3-nikon-d7000-presets-the-saga-continues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay - so I have been screwing around with the presets that I envisioned releasing to all of you Aperture 3 users for months. In case you think that I have been slacking off here - think different. I have come to the conclusion that I cannot release a product that I feel comfortable with. Namely a product that I would find acceptable as a consumer if I was expecting a quick and easy way to duplicate Nikon NX2 or OOC JPEG Picture Control settings.</p>

<p>It has nothing to do with me not understanding the differences in gamma/contrast - saturation - or more importantly color (HSL values) rendered by Nikon NX2 vs Aperture 2 - I have been messing with this since Aperture V1 when the differences were HUGE on the Nikon D2 series of cameras. Since then it has gotten a lot &#8220;better&#8221; but with smaller degrees of the same nagging issues. The problem with packaging a canned solution is that there are too many variables to make a product that is easy to use, makes any sense, saves time and produces results that are close enough for me to be comfortable with.</p>

<p>I have sliced this many many different ways and the color adjustments are highly dependent on the color of the light, WB settings when taking the image, and the scene. Matching a color target under one set of conditions is not going to cut it in real world use. Breaking up the presets with a bunch of &#8220;if this&#8221; then use preset X and preset Y otherwise do something different is too complicated to be of much use. It&#8217;s trying to duplicate what I do with my NEF files depending on too many variables - it&#8217;s easier to just do it yourself visually rather than dealing with interpreting the conditions and wading through a few dozen preset combinations.</p>

<p>So&#8230; I give up. No one set of &#8220;standard, vivid, neutral, portrait, and landscape&#8221; presets is going to produce accurate and acceptable results under diverse real world shooting conditions.</p>

<p>About the only thing that might at all be interesting to you as a consolation prize is the gamma/contrast curves that I use to match Nikon Picture controls - unfortunately this only goes half way. If anyone is interested in just the gamma/contrast/saturation presets without the color I will go through the trouble of posting them for purchase for like a buck or something (need to pay for bandwidth somehow&#8230;) please let me know - and sorry I cannot move this particular mountain&#8230;</p>

<p>[poll id=&#8221;29&#8221;]</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhotoPlus Gear - Follow Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/03/photoplus-gear-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/03/photoplus-gear-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My <a href="http://photo.rwboyer.com/2011/11/02/photoplus-expo-whatever/">little rant yesterday</a> on the state of affairs at PhotoPlus may have been a little over the top and a little too anti-gear. Let me clarify just a bit of my thoughts briefly. As photographers we all share a special relationships with the tools that allow us to make images. I admit this freely. If your camera doesn&#8217;t feel good you will not be at your best when using it. If you don&#8217;t get along with it very well, it is not going to be a productive relationship. Using different cameras causes you to make different images. It really does. You have no choice in many many cases. In other cases this might be a bit more subliminal but there none the less.</p>

<p>In this context I was not at all critisizing the denizens of the show. I was just amazed that the conversation always went towards gear. Gear that in my mind did nothing to help me in 99%  of the images that I desire to make. There was nobody talking about how anything at the show related at all to their endeavors as a photographer. They were talking about the gear in isolation. As something to be discussed as an ends in and of itself, without context.</p>

<p>Does everyone else really shoot 5, 8, 10, 12 frames per second a lot? Do they need more speed in order to be capable of dealing with their chosen subject matter? Is image quality only measured by the degree of magnification you get when you hit Option+1 or the &#8220;Z&#8221; key? Does the degree of noise when you shoot images in really really dim crappy light matter that much? Do people really care that much about dim crappy light?</p>

<p>Maybe I am the odd man out here but I have a really good idea about how I want images that I actually care to make look. I have a reasonable idea of what makes me comfortable when I shoot. I have some parameters as to the image aesthetics I desire. I don&#8217;t think my chosen subject matter is that far off from a large portion of photographers out there. I don&#8217;t shoot sports, wildlife, or anything really far away. I don&#8217;t have any reason to shoot in the dark. I like to shoot things relatively close - usually people. I like window light and a few other situations. I know what the exposure equation is. I like small very large aperture lenses. I like solid, small cameras with simple controls. I like big viewfinders. I can take or leave autofocus becuase in my 3-9 foot range (vast majority of the time) autofocus at wide apertures is really not that useful and in most cases counter productive.</p>

<p>I feel really let down by camera makers. They make no digital products anywhere near a reasonable price that I am interested in. Almost without fail they all make the same camera over and over and over and over again. They look the same, they act the same. They are too too big, the sensors are too small to render images the way I like to see them unless I want an even bigger camera. Noise at crazy ISO,s has gone down and image magnification ability has gone up but generally speaking the image quality that I care about in terms of aesthetics is wholely lacking with the exception of crazy big and crazy expensive products.</p>

<p>Where a camera similar to a <a href="http://photo.rwboyer.com/2011/06/28/new-nikon-digital-camera-annoucement/">digital FM/FE</a>? Where are small light reasonibly priced large aperture lenses? Either crazy expensive or boutique crazy expensive. I can honestly say that I have own not one digital camera that I liked in any way better than most of my film gear. Not one. Too big, too ugly, too heavy, and with minor exceptions (which do not apply to subjects I am interested in) not one helped me in any way to make images that I couldn&#8217;t make before. Not one produced images that I found as aestetically pleasing without a lot of messing around in post let alone &#8220;better&#8221;. We are all a decade into &#8220;product maturity&#8221; and the glow and hope has worn off for me. I am convinced we will get less diversity in design and features rather than more. I am convinced anything that remotely interests me will be priced so far into the stratusphere if they are available that they will make no sense for me to persue.</p>

<p>My reaction to PhotoPlus was to immediately purchase these as soon as I got home. One of them was actually purchased while I was still in NYC.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/P1020241.jpg"></p>

<p>A silver OM-1, a silver OM-1n, a black OM-1, two black OM-2&#8217;s - on an &#8220;n&#8221; the other a bit older. All of them work fine, the 28mm, 50mm f1.8, 50mm f1.4, and 135mm all came with the cameras and included the little Olympus lens cases as a bonus. I spent about $150 for the lot of them. Why Olympus? Well I already have enough Nikon gear to last me 3 lifetimes, same goes for Hasselblad and I have always love the OM system for it&#8217;s tiny dimensions and giant (not so much with the OM3/4) uncluttered viewfinders and figured I would corner the market before everyone else figured out the digital tread mill blows and the promised land sucks.</p>

<p>I am seriously thinking on doing an available light workshop - I know it sounds kind of lame but have been surprised by how little experience people have at using available light. I put up a post on window light a year ago and joked about a workshop. A half dozen folks have contacted me about participating.</p>

<p>Of course I would not make film a requirement but I am thinking about having a bunch of film cameras available with giant aperture lenses and springing for a roll of portra for anyone that would like to try it during the workshop.</p>

<p>Anyone else interested in a workshop focusing on the subject and using available light creatively? Would it be cool to try out some film in a simple vintage camera while you were there or is that just dumb?</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhotoPlus Expo = Whatever]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/02/photoplus-expo-whatever/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/11/02/photoplus-expo-whatever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, here is my report from NYC PhotoPlus. I know, I am a terrible reporter as this is old news considering that the event was at the end of last week and anyone that gives a rat&#8217;s a<em></em> was probably being updated via 18 real time feeds. In any case I figured I would give my quite jaded 2 cents.</p>

<p>Overall I was bored. Bored bored BORED. The most exciting thing that I saw was a couple of new papers - actually I didn&#8217;t see them, my buddy did and he told me about them. They sounded really exciting. I know that you think I am nuts getting excited about something like paper but at least that means a couple of us still produce real tangible prints from photos that we bother to make.</p>

<p>For some reason everyone else seemed much more interested in trying to discover what mo-better-faster-stronger-megapixel crap is going to be available to shell out a bunch of money on so they can chuck the stuff they just bought last year. Who cares. There was also a lot of interest in stuff to publish more crappy images faster and faster in higher quantities to the web. I am serious. Yes - more images faster. Like realtime snap-publish.</p>

<p>Color me not impressed. Actually color me depressed. What got me in that state of mind really quick was the casual conversations that I had with folks that I ran into. I swear I did not lead these conversations - I was a passive participant. With one and only one exception in two full days I did not hear anyone bring up anything about anything but gear. Gear, gear, gear, and more gear. Nobody actually talked photographs and what they were doing, why they were doing it or any subject remotely about how their images look. The entire conversation without fail was about gear. The one exception was a long chat I had with a <a href="http://www.modernassembly.blogspot.com/">very interesting woman</a> and I don&#8217;t even remember what kind of camera she was using. Some sort of DX Nikon maybe? We talked about images and subject matter - stuff that is actually the real focus (pardon me - had to say it) of the image making endeavor.</p>

<p>Here is my gear report - short and sweet. Hasselblad and some other medium format camera makers sell some products that will give you really good looking images (sort of like film does) for somewhere between $30,000 and $50,000. Nikon has an itty-bitty camera with an itty-bitty sensor that takes images that look nowhere near as good as film but look reasonable with not a lot of thought. Everyone has gigantic DSLR&#8217;s about three times the size and weight of film SLRs that also make reasonable images in the dark with not a whole lot of noise but generally don&#8217;t look as good as film does but they do it without any thought. They do it fast. They do it WAY better than the DSLR you had last year and will be garbage next year. Whatever reason you images look like crap - the new cameras will fix - until next year. Step right up.</p>

<p>In all seriousness - if bigger, badder, faster is interesting to you Sony is kicking ass in that department. That little flood thing is holding up product at the moment but the latest round of bigger badder faster has Sony producing some seriouly mosterous products. Holy crap. If Nikon and Canon didn&#8217;t have a bunch of brand loyalty and zealotry they would be in huge trouble. Maybe they will be in a year or two. The A77 is a monster for dirt cheap.</p>

<p>There you have it - your somewhat belated report. Entirely objective. If you missed it don&#8217;t worry about it, you didn&#8217;t miss much. If you plan on going next year - plan on bringing some drinking buddies and use it as an excuse to party while doing &#8220;business&#8221;.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NYC - Color - D7000 - Etc]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/26/nyc-color-d7000-etc/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/26/nyc-color-d7000-etc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long time no see.</p>

<p>I have been crazy busy over the last few weeks. Daughter No. 1 is having her first baby, My friend and colleague just acquired $50K worth of Hasselblad 50 megapixel goodness he needed some help sorting out. A little work on some other projects. Getting ready for a new workshop promotion (not mine - I am helping with the media production for someone else). Tearing my hair out over the D7000 presets, etc, etc. Wrapping things up so that I can take two days off to play around in NYC for photoplusexpo or whatever it&#8217;s called this week.</p>

<p>First off the D7000 color presets. Grrrrr. I have been fiddling with these things for over a month. It&#8217;s not a matter of being done or not done. It&#8217;s more a matter of playing with compromises and usability for something that I am actually going to charge a few bucks for. First off - they are not perfect in every picture taking scenario. They cannot be due to issues I have described before regarding the closeness or lack of differentiation in certain hues. Maddening. This makes me even more curious as to how well the Datacolor calibrator for Aperture 3 actually works considering it uses the same mechanisms I am trying to use for the presets. My bet - not that well depending on how obsessive you are.</p>

<p>In the past I have developed Aperture presets that get me close to what I want in my Nikon cameras and then gone from there with fine tuning of the color based on the scene. In putting together something that I am actually going to charge a couple of bucks for I am trying to somehow bundle my thought process into quick and easy with not a lot of additional thought required to get Nikon shooters to where they want to be. Not easy. Still working on it. Maybe I will just release what I have now at a really low price as version 1 with full disclosure (unlike some other folk that don&#8217;t even mess with the hue issues - huh) and develop a version 2 using customer feedback with what would be most valuable to people&#8230; with a discounted of free update to version 2? Suggestions?</p>

<p>Moving on - color. When I shoot projects for myself I tend toward shooting black and white. I love black and white for my own personal endeavors. Way back when I shot commercial work I shot 99% color and color was very important to me. I have ranted before that for the most part digital color sucks with a few rare exceptions that cost major bucks. It takes way way too much work that I am not interested in doing to make it look &#8220;real&#8221; and &#8220;good&#8221; and &#8220;natural&#8221; - especially skin. Film = shoot and done. Digital = shoot and mess about with it to get it anywhere near as real/good/natural as film. I am not talking about LOUD - loud is easy. I am actually starting to think that as a society our collective visual perception is being dulled and slowly our perception is moving towards only being able to evaluate grotesque differences because of how lousy most of the color we all see everyday in photographs. No subtlety at all. Subtlety and gradation have left the building.</p>

<p>Case in point. Here is a D7000 RAW processed and neutralized - the grays at least via the latest greatest version of Adobe ACR&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/DSC_3063.jpg"></p>

<p>And here is the wildest color neg film available, Kodak Ektar 100.</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/2011-008-28cn.jpg"></p>

<p>Yea, yea, yea, I didn&#8217;t focus the film perfectly, I didn&#8217;t even bother to blow the dust of the negative prior to scanning so it&#8217;s gritty and grimy. Yea the digital looks clean and smoooooooooooooooth. Both images have a very similar overall and mid-tone contrast curve. If at all possible try to just look at the color. Some of you may prefer the digital color - my bet if you do is because that is what you are so accustomed to seeing at this point. Now look closer - see the lack of differentiation in the yellow and the green patch above and to the left? Look at the purple patch - now the red - now the blue that is close to a primary. I am sitting here looking at the images as well as the actual color target - forget accuracy, let&#8217;s talk &#8220;real&#8221;. The D7000 version looks sort of like a cartoon compared to the film. In fact that is the real issue - it&#8217;s very much like a cartoon. Deep colors are not &#8220;deep&#8221; - they are thin and just build up saturation. The deeper and more saturated the patch on the chart the more apparent it is. Look at the darkest/deepest/most saturated of all the colors in each image and this should be amazingly evident.</p>

<p>Secret #452: Putting more saturation in is EASY. Taking it out does not improve things or increase subtle gradation - it just makes it dull. Loud cartoony color with no differentiation and subtle gradation is not &#8220;good color&#8221;. Just my opinion.</p>

<p>NYC - photoplusexposuperdupershow, or whatever it&#8217;s called. Anyone else going - I am leaving tomorrow and coming back Friday night. Drop me a line and maybe we can meet up&#8230; Always love chatting it up with fellow photo-nut-cases.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aperture 3 Nikon D7000 Presets - The Story]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/07/aperture-3-nikon-d7000-presets-the-story/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/07/aperture-3-nikon-d7000-presets-the-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nope, not another excuse or explanation about my bogus post the other day&#8230; Just some answers to a bunch of questions that I received via email over the last week regarding the, how, what, why, where, on the D7000 presets for Aperture 3. So not in any order here we go&#8230;</p>

<p>What is the issue here, why the need for presets, and what do you mean when you talk about the color being &#8220;off&#8221;. Answer &#8230; hmmm. Let&#8217;s take the color being &#8220;off&#8221; first and I will get you the others as I move through this a in a bit. Take a look at the image below&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/D7000-color-AP30170.jpg"></p>

<p>This color chart which is a default Aperture 3 RAW conversion with no other settings applied showcases a few things. The first bugaboo is what I call the yellow-green crossover issue. Find the patch on the right side of the colorchecker that is clearly yellow (third row from the top and three over). Now look at the patch up and to the left of that. These two patches are soooooo close in hue that they are hard to separate that is because most greens are too yellow in the default conversion. Now the big problem is that if you shift this color to green - the yellows also go green, if you don&#8217;t all your greens look yellow. Big problem and one that is almost impossible to develop a preset that will render all scenes in a reasonable and attractive way. My presets will not deal with this completely for all scenes - you pretty much have to choose - optimal Nikon yellow (which are great) or better greens. Next look at the cyan patch in the top row. Also take note of the diagonal line of blue patches with the most saturated blue ending up at the bottom. Compare them to this next image which is NX2 color (standard picture control)</p>

<p><img src="http://photo.rwboyer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/D7000-color-NX20171.jpg"></p>

<p>Notice how different the blues are. Nikon blues are way more towards purple where Aperture 3&#8217;s are more towards green. Notice how the &#8220;cyan&#8221; patch up at the top is completely different - different hue - different everything. Neither of them are &#8220;correct&#8221; as I compare them to my color targets but here is the deal. If you match the Aperture 3 blues at the bottom other blues that shouldn&#8217;t be that purple go too purple in real world photographs. A good example is the sky. The sky is different hues depending on time of day, different days, time of year. Not just saturation - the actual hue - the color number. If you shift Aperture blues in general towards purple sometimes the sky goes tooo purple if it was in the range of blues that Aperture 3 doesn&#8217;t shift too much. Other times since Aperture 3 has a tendency more towards green it goes cyan if not shifted toward blue. Nikon NX2 doesn&#8217;t do this.The reset of the colors are not a big issue but these should be pretty clear to anyone that is not blind.</p>

<p>Now the rest of the answer&#8230; Default gamma or maybe contrast is a better term for everyone. The Nikon picture control settings have some pretty nice default contrast curves that people seem to like. Aperture 3&#8217;s default gamma is all over the map depending on what Nikon camera you are shooting. For the D7000 it&#8217;s not too horrible but still not as attractive as any of the OOC JPEG&#8217;s So the other aspect to my presets is matching the gamma/contrast curve for all the various Nikon picture controls as closely as possible which unfortunately is not just manipulating the end points of the curve it&#8217;s a bit more complicated.</p>

<p>Now, why is it taking me so long? To be blunt - no one preset is going to match Nikon color and gamma on any given scene. It cannot because of what we are left with after the initial Aperture 3 conversion. I have a work-flow and look that I like and deal with all of my Nikon RAW images individually. That&#8217;s pretty hard to package up in a preset. In fact I am not able to do that nor will I try. Instead I going to include a bunch of variations that should be generally useful starting points for a lot of images.</p>

<p>One set tries to deal with color, contrast, saturation, everything. Are they perfect - no. Especially if there are greens and yellows in the scene or depending on what the color of the sky was on that particular day. I am also providing another set that deals with gamma only - that&#8217;s it, no color adjustment whatsoever. Another set of presets deals with gamma and saturation with no hue shifts. Lastly some variations on dealing with only optimizing a particular set of colors. So, the presets are actually a bunch of presets depending on what would be a useful starting point for you, your work-flow, and your images. That and I have to test them against real world images to see how useful they are. You cannot just check them against this chart and be done with it.</p>

<p>That is one of the reasons I am very curious to see how the new Datacolor color calibrator for Aperture 3 actually works in the real world since it uses the selective color tool that I am using. My guess is it will not be that great. Unfortunately I don&#8217;t want to buy it just to find out how bad it is.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aperture 3 and the Nikon D7000 - Correction]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/07/aperture-3-and-the-nikon-d7000-correction/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/07/aperture-3-and-the-nikon-d7000-correction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay - so you read my long drawn out bunch of stuff the other day regarding how all of a sudden the Nikon D7000 NEF RAW processing was somehow magically fixed in Aperture 3. Well this is an official retraction of that statement. I was having a very very strange day when I posted that and somehow got a few of my 300 million versions of files that I am working on for the D7000 picture control presets mixed up and re-named.</p>

<p>Long story short - I screwed up. Nothing is fixed in Aperture 3. Same old, same old. That&#8217;s the bad news. The good news is that I don&#8217;t have to completely re-do all of my preset work and stand a good chance on getting version 1 of the D7000 Aperture 3 presets out the door this weekend.</p>

<p>Sorry for the confusion and mis-information, my bad.</p>

<p>Back to work&#8230;</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aperture 3 and the Nikon D7000]]></title>
    <link href="http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/05/aperture-3-and-the-nikon-d7000-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://code.rwboyer.com/blog/2011/10/05/aperture-3-and-the-nikon-d7000-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time somebody complained about how far off Aperture 3&#8217;s NEF processing was. That was me. Actually I complained about it incesantly since Aperture V1. My very very very first post to the Apple Aperture community forum way way back years ago was about how far off Aperture&#8217;s RAW decode was in terms of color from that of Nikon&#8217;s.</p>

<p>Fast forward. I get a brand new Nikon D7000 and no surprise, Aperture 3&#8217;s color is still way off. The blue&#8217;s are too cyan, the greens are too yellow, the yellows are too green, etc, etc. Pretty much the same formula that has been NEF processing in Aperture since the dawn of time. Yes the amount they are off, the degree to which they render in terms of saturation and density are again different but they are still the same general recipe.</p>

<p>The gamma and WB have gotten closer to Nikon&#8217;s with each NEF RAW implementation that Apple has done as new cameras have come down the pipeline but the color was still off. Over the course of a few years I have put some free presets out there for different Nikon camera models that get you closer to an NX2 decode in Aperture but they have not been complete and they were adjusted more or less to my tastes.</p>

<p>This time I decided to get as close as possible to all of the NX2 rendered Nikon Picture Control settings for the D7000. I have been refining them under different lighting conditions and different scenes for the last three weeks. I am on version 4 of my refinements to both the gamma as well as the color. I sat down yesterday to do what would be the final version 5 to be offered to all of you Aperture 3 Nikon shooters that have been living with this and guess what&#8230;</p>

<p>Everything changed. The latest greatest update for Aperture 3 and Apple&#8217;s Camera RAW that came out just a little while ago seemed to have changed everything. WTF? I need more time to investigate this and test it on a few different camera models but for the D7000 the color is as close as it has ever been to the way NX2 decodes NEF RAW files. I swear this is unbelievable. It&#8217;s still a little different but nowhere near the same degree that it used to be. The typical hue shifts that I have seen in the past and even prior to the last update are nowhere near what they were for the D7000.</p>

<p>In any case - I am re-doing the D7000 presets for all the Picture controls but even without them they are not nearly as ugly as they used to be. Of course I will match gamma and saturation as well in the presets. Hopefully they will be done by the end of the week.</p>

<p>Did anyone else notice this? Am I going mad? What the hell??? I will keep you updated as I continue to investigate this surprising turn of events.</p>

<p>RB</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
